Why are you tapping on it?
Doing this tells me where the
wood is rotten or eaten by bugs.
Bugs?
Wood-eating bugs.
Oops, found one.
Look here.
Ugh, gross!
All right, then let's burn this piece.
What happens if we just leave it?
When heavy rain fills the pond,
the sluice gate will break.
Hmm, why would it break?
From the water pressure.
Pressure is incredible. But just
one tiny hole should be fine, right?
No, no. As the saying goes, even a massive
levee can collapse from a single ant hole.
What does that mean?
It means even a sturdy
dike can be destroyed...
...starting from one little ant hole.
Always be careful, even with little things.
That's terrible. Then
everything would be flooded!
Indeed. And that's not all.
If the reservoir empties, crops won't grow,
and we won't have drinking water either.
Oh no, that's awful! I'll help you too.
Here.
Thank you. You're such a kind boy.
Hey Mokku!
Mokku!
Over here! Over here!
Why are you calling Mokku?
You don't get it? We're gonna use him.
Use him how?
The water's still cold, right?
So we put Mokku in the
water to flush out the fish.
Oh, I see. Good idea.
We're catching fish!
It's fun! Come over here!
Fish? What should I do?
I'm going!
Hey, Mokku!
Wait! I'm coming!
Hopeless boy.
He's only interested in playing.
All right, do your best! Did it slip away?
Go! Get 'em, get 'em, get 'em!
Get 'em, get 'em!
We did it!
Phew, I'm exhausted!
Man, look, that's carp!
The smell is incredible.
Look how plump it is! Let's
cook those bad boys up!
Honestly, my mouth is drooling
like crazy. I wonder why...
A fresh carp washed-sashimi,
ready to serve, baby!
Whoa, now you're talking, Boss!
You sure know your stuff when it
comes to good snacks, so no wonder
you know your way around cooking!
A bit of fresh carp sashimi...
I can't resist! I wonder why...
Idiot! I'm starving! That lunch of yours
didn't fill me up at all! Look at this!
I'm sorry, Boss.
All right, go swipe that carp!
W-What? No, I can't! At night
maybe, but in broad daylight...
You slow-witted fool. You've got a weasel's
last trick—a real good stinker—don't you?
But, Boss, that's what you use when
you're running away. I wonder why.
What do you mean "I wonder why"?!
You distract them with a stink...
...powerful enough to rip their
nose off, and that's your chance!
Hey, brilliant!
Ready?
Stand by!
Ready to go?
Gotta go! Gotta go! Gotta go!
He did it!
Boss, it's the wind's fault! It's the wind!
I wonder why.
Swish, swish, swish!
Get outta here! Shoo!
It came off!
It's detached!
What's this? A wood bug?
Huh? It looks just like
the bugs at the sluice gate!
I see, it washed down here.
Unbelievable, trying to eat my foot.
Did the bugs eat away at it and mess up
the measurements where his knee moves?
Could have.
Can you even walk like that?!
I think so, but...
This is weird...
He's broken! He's broken!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go home!
Damn that Franco!
Grandpa will make me a new one!
All done. Here is your new leg.
Cool!
It's the exact same size as the old one.
Here, let me attach it for you.
Well, no one will laugh
at you now. Try walking.
Thank you, Grandpa.
What is the matter?
I tripped.
Your leg won't move.
Mokku!
Grandpa, why did you
make me a leg like this?!
I want a leg that moves like before!
B-But even if you say that...
Grandpa has no idea
why it won't move either...
How nice...
When everyone else plays in the
river, they don't get wood bugs...
Even if they get muddy,
they're fine once they wash off!
And yet, I'm...
I hate this... I hate it! I don't
want to be a puppet anymore!
M-Mokku...
Don't you get it? Even if it's
made from fine oak, it won't move.
Not without the Oak Tree Fairy's power.
Aaah... I'm so hungry!
I've got to eat somehow! I wonder why.
Man, I want to eat carp. I've gotta
eat carp somehow. I want to eat carp.
Wait! I've got a great idea!
Jackpot! Time to eat!
Huh? A master who can make legs that move?
Shh! Keep your voice down!
That's right! There's a
master leg-maker around!
W-Where is this master?
You want us to tell you?
Please!
I could tell you, but not for free!
Yeah!
What do you mean? What should I do?
Oh, nothing much. Just lend us
a hand for a bit. Simple as that.
Even this is better than
not being able to move.
Mokku, what are you doing?
I'm leaving.
Leaving? Where to?
Leave me alone. What does it matter where?
Fine. If you want to know
that badly, I'll tell you.
I'm going to a master
puppet maker who's way...
...way better than Grandpa,
to have him make me a leg!
Much better?
That's right.
There's no master like that.
Yes, there is!
Nobody anywhere can make a
puppet that moves like a real human.
Yes, there is!
There really is! I heard all about him!
No, there isn't.
Goodbye.
Mokku!
Hmm, having legs that
won't move must be tough.
Come on, tell me. What
do you want me to do?
It's simple, really. Just catch two or
three fish from this reservoir for me.
Catch them? How, without any tools?
It's a piece of cake. Look, you just
open this floodgate and drain the water.
Then you can just grab 'em with
your bare hands without any gear.
All right, I'll try. But in return,
once I catch the fish, you have to...
I'm tellin' ya, you can move it!
Good boy, good boy. We
don't have to lift a finger...
...and we can eat all
we want, that's how it is.
As expected of you, Boss, your
mind is so sharp. I wonder why.
Hey, Mokku!
If you do that, the water will rush out
and the whole town will be in big trouble!
What, you again?!
Stop it, Mokku! Are you
trying to flood the whole town?!
Shut up! I want legs! Legs that move!
Hey, hurry it up!
If the handle won't work, why
not try smashing it with a rock?
I'm starving... I want food...
Boss, it's raining.
Shall we go?
Where are you going?
To take shelter from the
rain. I hate getting wet.
Please tell me if you're leaving.
You idiot! I haven't eaten
in ages, this is ridiculous!
That Kenken... next time I
see him, he won't get off easy!
The ants have it nice. Under the big
tree, not having to worry about the rain.
I wonder if the floodgate is okay...
The spot where I hit it with the rock...
There's so much water...
It's the spot where I
hit it with the rock...
It won't stop...
As they say, even a massive dike
can collapse from a single ant hole.
Even a sturdy dike can be
destroyed by one tiny ant hole!
Grandpa!
What are you dawdling for?!
Hurry up and plug the leak!
H-How?
Stuff it with wood!
Wood? There isn't any wood around here!
Yes there is! You're made of wood!
M-Me? You're telling me to use
my own body to stop the water?
There's no other way!
No! I don't want to!
There it is!
What are you messing around for?!
Hurry, or the floodgate will break!
No way! If I lose these arms and
legs, there are no replacements!
Fine! Then let the whole
town drown in water!
Grandpa will just drown and die, too!
Thank goodness, it held.
Mokku!
Mokku...
Mokku, you...
You drove your own body into it for me...?
Well, Grandpa is going
to go deliver this order.
You are...
Mokku, I saw everything. Your noble
deed. You did well to save the townspeople.
You were magnificent. Truly magnificent.
I have come to give you life once again.
I can move!
Please, wait! How was I restored?
You sacrificed your precious limbs to
save others.
Compassion for people...
...that is the feeling known as love.
Your love...
...has given you life.
My love did?
Come on!
Hey, that's dangerous!
Sorry, sorry!
Mokku!
Look out if you're not paying
attention! We're in the middle of a match!
Hey, Mokku!
- Wait
- Hurry up Mokku!
Nice going, Mokku!
Mokku becomes friends with Chikaro, a
monkey who can speak just like a human.
Learning that Chikaro lives in a
wealthy mansion, Kenken and the others...
...threaten Mokku to
make him bring them food.
However, when Mokku is
caught stealing the food...
...he ends up chained
up along with Chikaro...
...who is about to
be sold to a circus.
Look forward to next week's
Kashi no Ki Mokku!